Hi, my name's Lincoln Ward.
I'm the director of the Austin Tennis Center here in Austin, Texas.
Today we're going to talk about how long the string is on your tennis racket.
You'd be surprised that this, this little frame holds almost, or over thirty-six feet of string.
These, the, the mains, which run up and down on your racket, use about eighteen feet worth of string.
These cross sections use about sixteen feet of string.
However; the string, the exact amount of string you're going to use on your racket will also depend on the size of your, the head of your racket.
As this, this head is much smaller than this head, it's going to use a considerable amount less of string.
But any time you string your racket, you want to set aside about thirty-six feet, linear feet of string for your racket.
The, the tie-offs will, will also add a couple of extra feet, and you have to cut off.
Not extra feet, but a couple extra inches worth of cut off.
But that's pretty much the length of the string on your tennis racket.